<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Symphony/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Symphony/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-10T20:33:36+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Symphony/</id><title type="html">Symphony</title><subtitle>“Welcome to the world of Symphony”.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Da Open Code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Symphony/blog/Da-Open-Code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Da Open Code" /><published>2017-04-04T18:47:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-04T18:47:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Symphony/blog/Da-Open-Code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Symphony/blog/Da-Open-Code">&lt;p&gt;HOLA READERS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog and in this I will be introducing you with &lt;em&gt;Da Open Code&lt;/em&gt;.
The title is inspired from Dan Brown’s &lt;em&gt;Da Vinci Code&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Da Open Code, refers to the source code that is openly available. Can you guess what I am talking about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You guessed right,I am talking about &lt;em&gt;Open Source&lt;/em&gt;, and contributing to it.
In this blog I am going to introduce you to what is Open Source, why Open Source and
how Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT IS OPEN SOURCE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it is pretty simple to understand what open source is, you just put your project along with
it’s code on display for other people to see and build from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question that pops up in anyone’s mind, Why the hell would anyone do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, trust me I had this question too. But then I googled it and then realised the power of open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to the next part of my blog, which is, &lt;strong&gt;WHY OPEN SOURCE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Famous projects like, LINUX, various android, machine learning libraries, web development toolkits are being developed through open source, reason being these projects are at this level just because, they were built by best developers which contributed to these projects from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, you can be a part of a project in which you want to contribute, being part of dream project, that too sitting at your own home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this various internship projects, like GSoC, Outreachy are held which selects developers by taking in consideration their contribution to the open source projects and community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings to the last part, which is, &lt;strong&gt;HOW OPEN SOURCE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few online websites like GitHub, and BitBucket which provides the users to put their projects online, fork a project, in which they want to contribute. Add contributors to their project, accept a request and watch or star interesting projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming blogs, I’ll be introducing about how to work with git and github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then Ciao!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">HOLA READERS!</summary></entry></feed>